<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<parameter name="allow_console_password_only"
                      section="global"
                      type="bool"
                      rust_type="bool"
                      documented="true"
                      domain_specific="false"
                      order="1400"
                     >
<description>
Enables password-only (single-factor) authentication for local console logins
(e.g., TTY, GDM, SDDM, LightDM). When enabled, Himmelblau will attempt to authenticate
using only the user's password for local sessions. If Microsoft Entra ID
requires MFA (based on Conditional Access policies), the user will be prompted
for MFA automatically.

This option does
.B NOT
affect remote authentication methods such as SSH, which
always require MFA (unless the user has Hello + TOTP configured or allow_remote_hello is enabled).

Remote connections are detected using multiple signals:
.RS
.IP \(bu 2
PAM_RHOST \- If the remote host is set to a non-localhost value
.IP \(bu 2
PAM_SERVICE \- If the service name matches entries in
.B password_only_remote_services_deny_list
.IP \(bu 2
PAM_TTY \- If the terminal name contains "ssh" (fallback check)
.RE

For Microsoft Entra ID, this option requires the device to be domain-joined,
matching the behavior of Microsoft-managed devices. Users can still use Hello
PIN authentication if it is configured. To require MFA for all logins
(including local console), set this option to
.B false.

.PP
When a generic OIDC provider is configured (see
.B oidc_issuer_url
), this option also enables password-only login using the OIDC Resource Owner
Password Credentials (ROPC) grant. It is only offered when the provider
advertises the
.B password
grant type in its discovery document and does not require the device to be
domain-joined; providers that disable this grant fall back to the
device-authorization (browser) flow. If the provider additionally requires MFA,
authentication falls back to the device flow automatically.
</description>
<conf_description>Allow password-only auth for local console sessions.</conf_description>
<default>true</default>
<default_const>DEFAULT_CONSOLE_PASSWORD_ONLY</default_const>
<example>allow_console_password_only = false</example>
</parameter>
